<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://tardito.dev/blog</id>
    <title>Luca Tardito Blog</title>
    <updated>2021-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tardito.dev/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Luca Tardito Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://tardito.dev/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cinque Terre]]></title>
        <id>cinqueterre</id>
        <link href="https://tardito.dev/blog/cinqueterre"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cinque Terre is a region in Italy that consists of five coastal towns located in the Liguria region. It is known for its beautiful scenery, which includes colorful houses built into the cliffs, vineyards, and olive groves. It is a popular tourist destination for its beaches, hiking trails, and seafood.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cinque Terre is a region in Italy that consists of five coastal towns located in the Liguria region. It is known for its beautiful scenery, which includes colorful houses built into the cliffs, vineyards, and olive groves. It is a popular tourist destination for its beaches, hiking trails, and seafood.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Picture brussels" src="/assets/images/primary-646c4329836fe4a59838936c91aef8e4.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do">What to do<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-do" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li><p>Hike the trails: Cinque Terre is home to a network of trails that offer stunning views of the coast and the towns.</p></li><li><p>Visit the beaches: The region has several beautiful beaches, including Monterosso al Mare, Vernazza, and Riomaggiore.</p></li><li><p>Explore the towns: Each of the five towns has its own character and charm. Take some time to wander the narrow streets, visit the local churches and museums, and try the local food and wine.</p></li><li><p>Go fishing: Cinque Terre is known for its seafood, and you can try your hand at fishing in the Mediterranean Sea.</p></li><li><p>Take a boat tour: A boat tour is a great way to see the region's coastline and get a different perspective on the towns. You can also go scuba diving or snorkeling to see the marine life.</p></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Picture brussels" src="/assets/images/secondary-46d391c6dd123864bd18b7f881ff5e26.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-eat">What to eat<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-eat" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li><p>Pesto: Pesto is a sauce made from basil, pine nuts, and garlic, and it is a specialty of the Liguria region. It is often served with pasta, but you can also find it used as a condiment on sandwiches or as a topping for pizza.</p></li><li><p>Focaccia: Focaccia is a flat bread that is popular in Cinque Terre. It is typically topped with herbs, olives, and salt, and it is often served as an appetizer or snack.</p></li><li><p>Trofie al pesto: Trofie is a type of pasta that is native to Liguria, and it is often served with pesto sauce.</p></li><li><p>Seafood: Cinque Terre is known for its seafood, and you can find a variety of dishes featuring fish, shellfish, and other seafood.</p></li><li><p>Gelato: No trip to Italy is complete without trying some gelato, and Cinque Terre is no exception. Be sure to sample the local flavors, such as lemon and basil.</p></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Third" src="/assets/images/thernary-fa6181e9fa14c6a0f3b888039fe6d24f.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Tardito</name>
            <uri>https://www.instagram.com/luca.tardito/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="travels" term="travels"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brussels in a day]]></title>
        <id>brussels</id>
        <link href="https://tardito.dev/blog/brussels"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brussels is the capital city of Belgium, and is located in central Belgium. It is known for its historic landmarks and cultural institutions, as well as its role as the seat of the European Union. The city is known for its chocolate, waffles, and beer, and is often referred to as the "Capital of Europe".]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Brussels is the capital city of Belgium, and is located in central Belgium. It is known for its historic landmarks and cultural institutions, as well as its role as the seat of the European Union. The city is known for its chocolate, waffles, and beer, and is often referred to as the "Capital of Europe".</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Picture brussels" src="/assets/images/main-d27dd7f02df4744b132560aafc2c6617.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do">What to do<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-do" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>Visit the Atomium, a modernist steel structure that was built for the 1958 World's Fair.</li><li>Explore the Grand Place, a UNESCO World Heritage Site and the central square of Brussels, which is surrounded by historic guildhalls and the city's Town Hall.</li><li>Take a tour of the European Union institutions, including the European Commission and the European Parliament.
Visit the Manneken Pis, a iconic bronze statue of a urinating boy that has become a symbol of the city.</li><li>Try some of the local cuisine, including Belgian waffles, chocolate, and beer. There are many restaurants and cafes throughout the city that serve these dishes.</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Picture brussels" src="/assets/images/secondary-c2c4bb034387920977688003f967c366.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-eat">What to eat<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-eat" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>Belgian waffles: These are a popular street food in Brussels, and are made with a thick, fluffy batter that is cooked in a waffle iron. They are often served with whipped cream and fruit.</li><li>Belgian chocolate: Belgium is known for its high-quality chocolate, and there are many chocolate shops throughout Brussels where you can try a variety of different chocolates.</li><li>Moules-frites: This is a traditional Belgian dish that consists of mussels and fries. The mussels are usually served in a broth made with white wine and shallots.</li><li>Stoemp: This is a traditional Belgian dish made with mashed potatoes and vegetables, such as carrots, Brussels sprouts, or turnips. It is often served as a side dish.</li><li>Belgian beer: Belgium is home to a wide variety of beers, including lambics, saisons, and abbey beers. There are many bars and breweries in Brussels where you can try different types of Belgian beer.</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Third" src="/assets/images/third-c7533cb17286f5d396e1193b0fedb3c5.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Tardito</name>
            <uri>https://www.instagram.com/luca.tardito/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="travels" term="travels"/>
    </entry>
</feed>