<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://tardito.dev/blog</id>
    <title>Luca Tardito Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://tardito.dev/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Luca Tardito Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://tardito.dev/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cinque Terre]]></title>
        <id>cinqueterre</id>
        <link href="https://tardito.dev/blog/cinqueterre"/>
        <updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cinque Terre is a region in Italy that consists of five coastal towns located in the Liguria region. It is known for its beautiful scenery, which includes colorful houses built into the cliffs, vineyards, and olive groves. It is a popular tourist destination for its beaches, hiking trails, and seafood.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cinque Terre is a region in Italy that consists of five coastal towns located in the Liguria region. It is known for its beautiful scenery, which includes colorful houses built into the cliffs, vineyards, and olive groves. It is a popular tourist destination for its beaches, hiking trails, and seafood.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Manarola" src="/assets/images/primary-646c4329836fe4a59838936c91aef8e4.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do">What to do<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-do" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li><p>Walk: Cinque Terre are connected with a network of trails that offer stunning views of the coast and the towns. The avarage time to go from a town to another is two hours but there is always the train alternative which stops in every of the five towns.</p></li><li><p>Explore the towns: Each of the five towns has its own character and charm. Take some time to wander the narrow streets, visit the local churches and museums, and try the local food and wine.</p></li><li><p>Visit the beaches: The region has several beautiful beaches, including Monterosso al Mare, Vernazza, and Riomaggiore.</p></li><li><p>Take the ferry: The ferry is a great way to see the coastline from a different perspective while moving from one town to another.</p></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Grapes" src="/assets/images/secondary-46d391c6dd123864bd18b7f881ff5e26.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-eat">What to eat<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-eat" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li><p>Focaccia: Focaccia is a flat bread that is popular in Cinque Terre. It is typically topped with herbs, olives, and salt, and it is often served as an appetizer or snack. If you want to have a real Ligurian experiance try a breakfast with warm Focaccia and Cappuccino.</p></li><li><p>Pesto: Pesto is a sauce made from basil, pine nuts, and garlic, and it is a specialty of the Liguria region. It is often served with Trofie, a type of pasta that is native to Liguria.</p></li><li><p>Seafood: Cinque Terre is known for its seafood, and you can find a variety of dishes featuring fish, shellfish, and other seafood.</p></li><li><p>Gelato: No trip to Italy is complete without trying some gelato, and Cinque Terre is no exception. Be sure to sample the local flavors, such as lemon and basil.</p></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="The port" src="/assets/images/thernary-fa6181e9fa14c6a0f3b888039fe6d24f.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Tardito</name>
            <uri>https://www.instagram.com/luca.tardito/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="travels" term="travels"/>
        <category label="italy" term="italy"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brussels]]></title>
        <id>brussels</id>
        <link href="https://tardito.dev/blog/brussels"/>
        <updated>2022-06-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brussels is the capital city of Belgium, and is located in central Belgium. It is known for its historic landmarks and cultural institutions, as well as its role as the seat of the European Union. The city is known for its chocolate, waffles, and beer, and is often referred to as the "Capital of Europe".]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Brussels is the capital city of Belgium, and is located in central Belgium. It is known for its historic landmarks and cultural institutions, as well as its role as the seat of the European Union. The city is known for its chocolate, waffles, and beer, and is often referred to as the "Capital of Europe".</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Brussels" src="/assets/images/main-d27dd7f02df4744b132560aafc2c6617.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do">What to do<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-do" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>Visit the Atomium, a modernist steel structure that was built for the 1958 World's Fair.</li><li>Explore the Grand Place, a UNESCO World Heritage Site and the central square of Brussels, which is surrounded by historic guildhalls and the city's Town Hall.</li><li>Take a tour of the European Union institutions, including the European Commission and the European Parliament.
Visit the Manneken Pis, a iconic bronze statue of a urinating boy that has become a symbol of the city.</li><li>Try some of the local cuisine, including Belgian waffles, chocolate, and beer. There are many restaurants and cafes throughout the city that serve these dishes.</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Houses" src="/assets/images/secondary-c2c4bb034387920977688003f967c366.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-eat">What to eat<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-eat" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>Belgian waffles: These are a popular street food in Brussels, and are made with a thick, fluffy batter that is cooked in a waffle iron. They are often served with whipped cream and fruit.</li><li>Belgian chocolate: Belgium is known for its high-quality chocolate, and there are many chocolate shops throughout Brussels where you can try a variety of different chocolates.</li><li>Moules-frites: This is a traditional Belgian dish that consists of mussels and fries. The mussels are usually served in a broth made with white wine and shallots.</li><li>Stoemp: This is a traditional Belgian dish made with mashed potatoes and vegetables, such as carrots, Brussels sprouts, or turnips. It is often served as a side dish.</li><li>Belgian beer: Belgium is home to a wide variety of beers, including lambics, saisons, and abbey beers. There are many bars and breweries in Brussels where you can try different types of Belgian beer.</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Gallery" src="/assets/images/third-c7533cb17286f5d396e1193b0fedb3c5.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Tardito</name>
            <uri>https://www.instagram.com/luca.tardito/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="travels" term="travels"/>
        <category label="belgium" term="belgium"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Miami]]></title>
        <id>miami</id>
        <link href="https://tardito.dev/blog/miami"/>
        <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Miami is a city located in southeastern Florida in the United States. It is known for its beautiful beaches, vibrant nightlife, and diverse culture. It is also a major center for finance, trade, and entertainment in the region.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Miami is a city located in southeastern Florida in the United States. It is known for its beautiful beaches, vibrant nightlife, and diverse culture. It is also a major center for finance, trade, and entertainment in the region.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Miami" src="/assets/images/primary-7eacec85ac47e7c9df8b0b942e855c2d.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do">What to do<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-do" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li><p>Explore Miami Beach: Miami is home to some of the most beautiful beaches in the world, the most famous are located in South Beach surranded by tall buildings with long beaches and colorful lifeguard towers.</p></li><li><p>Go to Little Havana: A <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/sQYiAEAcbixdBhNk6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">neighborhood</a> that is home to a large population of Cuban immigrants and their descendants. It is known for its lively atmosphere, colorful street art, and delicious Cuban food.</p></li><li><p>Visit the <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/8WZ5JXpTXnPG22Bd6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bayside Marketplace</a>: Bayside Marketplace is a shopping and entertainment complex located in downtown Miami, Florida. It is situated along the waterfront of Biscayne Bay and features a variety of retail stores, restaurants, and cafes. The complex is divided into two levels, with the upper level featuring open-air shopping and the lower level featuring a food court and live entertainment.</p></li><li><p>Take a boat: You can find different daily tours starting at Bayside Marketplace which allows you to see Miami from a different point of view while seeing celebrities villas.</p></li><li><p>Night out in <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/S1nUxcbu2cCzXobA6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ocean Drive</a>: A popular street and tourist destination, with millions of visitors each year coming to experience the lively atmosphere and soak up the sun on the beach. In the evening, Ocean Drive comes alive with music and crowds of people enjoying the nightlife.</p></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Little Havana" src="/assets/images/secondary-36ba7f567e46b897f39e78182a536f62.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-eat">What to eat<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-eat" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li><p><a href="https://goo.gl/maps/ANoKaXgrTjqxjCfk8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azucar's</a> ice cream: I was positively sursprised by the taste and quality of their ice cream, many particular flavours to try. When an Italian says an ice cream is good you should just try it.</p></li><li><p>Empanadas: Empanadas are savory pastries filled with a variety of fillings, such as meat, vegetables, or cheese. They are a popular snack in Miami and can be found at many local bakeries and food trucks.</p></li><li><p>Stone crabs: Miami is known for its delicious stone crabs, which are caught in the waters off the Florida coast and served chilled with mustard sauce. They are typically in season from October to May.</p></li><li><p>Key lime pie: Key lime pie is a Florida favorite and Miami is the perfect place to try it. This dessert is made with a graham cracker crust, a filling of sweetened, condensed milk and key lime juice, and a topping of whipped cream.</p></li><li><p>Ceviche: Ceviche is a popular seafood dish made with raw fish or shellfish that is "cooked" in citrus juice and seasoned with herbs and spices. It's a refreshing and light option that's perfect for a hot Miami day.</p></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Skyscrapers" src="/assets/images/third-a507557709eac1c68cf762ebde4906b0.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Tardito</name>
            <uri>https://www.instagram.com/luca.tardito/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="travels" term="travels"/>
        <category label="usa" term="usa"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lanzarote]]></title>
        <id>lanzarote</id>
        <link href="https://tardito.dev/blog/lanzarote"/>
        <updated>2021-11-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lanzarote is a Spanish island located in the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Africa. It is one of the Canary Islands and is known for its volcanic landscapes, black and white sandy beaches, and warm, dry climate. The island is a popular vacation destination for tourists from Europe and beyond.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lanzarote is a Spanish island located in the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Africa. It is one of the Canary Islands and is known for its volcanic landscapes, black and white sandy beaches, and warm, dry climate. The island is a popular vacation destination for tourists from Europe and beyond.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Lanzarote" src="/assets/images/main-5f171ced89be796069a0ad2df7aa838d.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do">What to do<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-do" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li><p>Visit the Timanfaya National Park, which features a moonscape of volcanic landscapes and geothermal activity. You can take a camel ride through the park or participate in a guided tour.</p></li><li><p>Head to the island's capital, Arrecife, to explore its charming Old Town and visit the Castillo de San José, a castle turned museum that houses a collection of modern art.</p></li><li><p>Take a dip in the crystal clear waters at one of the island's many beaches, such as Playa Blanca or Papagayo.</p></li><li><p>Go scuba diving or snorkeling to explore the island's vibrant marine life, including colorful fish and sea turtles.</p></li><li><p>Take a day trip to the neighboring island of Fuerteventura to experience its stunning beaches and sand dunes.</p></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Parrot" src="/assets/images/secondary-1550754d43aa4690326e3f237af136c2.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-eat">What to eat<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-eat" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li><p>Papas arrugadas: small, wrinkled potatoes boiled in saltwater and served with a spicy mojo sauce.</p></li><li><p>Sancocho canario: a hearty stew made with fish, potatoes, and vegetables.</p></li><li><p>Gofio: a toasted flour made from roasted grains, often mixed with water or milk to make a porridge or used as an ingredient in other dishes.</p></li><li><p>Queso de cabra: goat cheese produced on the island and often served as a tapa (small appetizer).</p></li><li><p>Mojo verde: a sauce made with parsley, garlic, oil, and vinegar, often served with grilled meats or papas arrugadas.</p></li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Sunset Lanzarote" src="/assets/images/third-c04dd198359ed68ea4bb24c4612371b6.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Tardito</name>
            <uri>https://www.instagram.com/luca.tardito/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="travels" term="travels"/>
        <category label="spain" term="spain"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lisbon]]></title>
        <id>lisbon</id>
        <link href="https://tardito.dev/blog/lisbon"/>
        <updated>2021-10-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lisbon is the capital and largest city of Portugal. It is located on the Atlantic coast and is known for its historic architecture and cultural landmarks, such as the Belem Tower and the Jeronimos Monastery. It is also known for its vibrant nightlife, delicious seafood, and picturesque neighborhoods like Alfama and Bairro Alto.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lisbon is the capital and largest city of Portugal. It is located on the Atlantic coast and is known for its historic architecture and cultural landmarks, such as the Belem Tower and the Jeronimos Monastery. It is also known for its vibrant nightlife, delicious seafood, and picturesque neighborhoods like Alfama and Bairro Alto.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Tram" src="/assets/images/primary-8fcdc0dba837a3f66d9bccbd79289733.jpg" width="4032" height="3024" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do">What to do<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-do" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>Visit the historic Belem Tower and Jeronimos Monastery, which are UNESCO World Heritage sites and iconic landmarks of Lisbon.</li><li>Take a tram ride through the city to explore the picturesque neighborhoods of Alfama, Bairro Alto, and Baixa.</li><li>Enjoy the nightlife and live music in neighborhoods like Bairro Alto and Principe Real.</li><li>Visit the Gulbenkian Museum, which has a wide collection of art and artifacts from around the world.</li><li>Take a day trip to Sintra, a town located outside of Lisbon, known for its beautiful palaces and castles, including the Pena Palace and the Moorish Castle.</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Belem" src="/assets/images/secondary-42a9ef472a07b19ae1a717ae6fbe8587.jpg" width="3024" height="4032" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-eat">What to eat<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-eat" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><ul><li>Try the traditional dish of "bacalhau" (salt cod) which is prepared in various styles such as "à brás" or "com natas" (with cream).</li><li>Sample some delicious seafood dishes, such as grilled sardines, octopus salad, and caldeirada (a fish stew).</li><li>Enjoy a "pastel de nata" (custard tart), a famous Portuguese pastry that originated in Lisbon's Belém neighborhood.</li><li>Try the traditional "cozido" a stew with various meats and vegetables, it is a hearty and comforting dish.</li><li>Enjoy a glass of "vinho verde" a young wine from the Minho region in the north of Portugal, it's refreshing and perfect for a hot summer day.</li></ul><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Lisbon street" src="/assets/images/third-31185ce4b88ba4e0dce5c4f96234dfbc.jpg" width="4032" height="3024" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Tardito</name>
            <uri>https://www.instagram.com/luca.tardito/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="travels" term="travels"/>
        <category label="portugal" term="portugal"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valcasotto]]></title>
        <id>valcasotto</id>
        <link href="https://tardito.dev/blog/valcasotto"/>
        <updated>2021-07-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Valcasotto valley protects its gem: A huge white palace, built in 1100 and surrounded by green mountains.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Valcasotto valley protects its gem: A huge white palace, built in 1100 and surrounded by green mountains.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1FqVaFZMFepoyt63HzJq-xt-wbSGdEjvs" alt="The Valcasotto's palace" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-history">The History<a class="hash-link" href="#the-history" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The Valcasotto palace served different purposes during its long history. It was initially built as a religious monastery for the Carthusians, a Roman Catholic religious order of monks known for their way of life which emphasizes solitude, prayer, and manual labor. After more than 700 years, it was purchased by the royal family, the Savoy. It was transformed into a hunting residence and it was one of the favorite places of Vittorio Emanuele II, the first Italian king. More recently, the Valcasotto palace was acquired by the Piedmont region and it has been opened to the public.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="The Valcasotto&amp;#39;s palace" src="/assets/images/second-ae0e06befcf1ec9bb6d7eb39d43008de.jpeg" width="1440" height="1440" class="img_ev3q"></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-to-visit-it">How to visit it<a class="hash-link" href="#how-to-visit-it" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>The best way to reach the <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/gs2JTXCthkbqRPSy7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Valcasotto palace location</a> is by car, a 30-minute drive from the closest town of Garessio along a small mountain paved road. The entrance to the main area is free, and a 10 euro ticket is required to visit the inside. The palace is often closed, so it is advisable to check the opening hours on <a href="https://www.comune.garessio.cn.it/en-us/vivere-il-comune/cosa-vedere/castello-di-casotto-sec-xii-17706-1-d1ce67833a3f32c7f08cd5dbdefa59a1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">its official website</a> before visiting. There is a small bar and restaurant located next to the entrance, which serves delicious sandwiches.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="The Valcasotto&amp;#39;s palace" src="/assets/images/third-be7ea2ef92dc6de4391c99ab1cbc3769.jpg" width="1440" height="1440" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Tardito</name>
            <uri>https://www.instagram.com/luca.tardito/</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="travels" term="travels"/>
        <category label="italy" term="italy"/>
    </entry>
</feed>